Principles of Macroeconomics
<div>
<para><emphasis effect="italics">Principles of Macroeconomics</emphasis> covers the scope and sequence for a one-semester economics course. The text also includes many current examples, including: the housing bubble and housing crisis, Zimbabwe’s hyperinflation, global unemployment, and the appointment of the United States’ first female Federal Reserve chair, Janet Yellen.</para>

<para>The pedagogical choices, chapter arrangements, and learning objective fulfillment were developed and vetted with feedback from educators dedicated to the project. The outcome is a balanced approach to economics, to both Keynesian and classical views, and to the theory and application of economics concepts. Current events are treated in a politically-balanced way, as well.</para>
</div>

Psychology
<div><para><emphasis effect="italics">Psychology</emphasis> is designed to meet the scope and sequence for the single-semester introduction to psychology course. For many students, this may be their only college-level psychology course. As such, this textbook provides an important opportunity for students to learn the core concepts of psychology and understand how those concepts apply to their lives. The authors strive to make psychology, as a discipline, interesting and accessible to students. A comprehensive coverage of core concepts is grounded in both classic studies and current and emerging research, including coverage of the DSM-5 in discussions of psychological disorders. The text incorporates discussions that reflect the diversity within the discipline, as well as the diversity of cultures and communities across the globe.</para></div>

Principles of Microeconomics
<div>
<para><emphasis effect="italics">Principles of Microeconomics</emphasis> covers the scope and sequence for a one-semester economics course. The text also includes many current examples, including; the Keystone Pipeline, Occupy Wall Street, and debates over the minimum wage.</para>

<para>The pedagogical choices, chapter arrangements, and learning objective fulfillment were developed and vetted with feedback from educators dedicated to the project. The outcome is a balanced approach to economics and to the theory and application of economics concepts. Current events are treated in a politically-balanced way, as well.</para>

<para><emphasis>Note:</emphasis> <emphasis effect="italics">Principles of Microeconomics</emphasis> PDF and web view versions have been updated to include current FRED (Federal Reserve Economic) data. </para>
</div>

Principles of Economics
<div>
<para><emphasis effect="italics">Principles of Economics</emphasis> covers the scope and sequence for a two-semester principles of economics course. The text also includes many current examples, including; discussions on the great recession, the controversy among economists over the Affordable Care Act (Obamacare), the recent government shutdown, and the appointment of the United States’ first female Federal Reserve chair, Janet Yellen.</para>

<para>The pedagogical choices, chapter arrangements, and learning objective fulfillment were developed and vetted with feedback from educators dedicated to the project. The outcome is a balanced approach to micro and macro economics, to both Keynesian and classical views, and to the theory and application of economics concepts. Current events are treated in a politically-balanced way, as well.</para>

<para><emphasis>Note:</emphasis> <emphasis effect="italics">Principles of Economics</emphasis> PDF and web view versions have been updated to include current FRED (Federal Reserve Economic) data. </para>
</div>

Algebra and Trigonometry
<div>
<para><emphasis effect="italics">Algebra and Trigonometry</emphasis> provides a comprehensive and multi-layered exploration of algebraic principles. The text is suitable for a typical introductory Algebra &amp; Trigonometry course, and was developed to be used flexibly. The modular approach and the richness of content ensures that the book meets the needs of a variety of programs. <emphasis effect="italics">Algebra and Trigonometry</emphasis> guides and supports students with differing levels of preparation and experience with mathematics. Ideas are presented as clearly as possible, and progress to more complex understandings with considerable reinforcement along the way. A wealth of examples – usually several dozen per chapter – offer detailed, conceptual explanations, in order to build in students a strong, cumulative foundation in the material before asking them to apply what they’ve learned.</para>
</div>

College Algebra
<para><emphasis effect="italics">College Algebra</emphasis> provides a comprehensive and multi-layered exploration of algebraic principles. The text is suitable for a typical introductory Algebra course, and was developed to be used flexibly. The modular approach and the richness of content ensures that the book meets the needs of a variety of programs. <emphasis effect="italics">College Algebra</emphasis> guides and supports students with differing levels of preparation and experience with mathematics. Ideas are presented as clearly as possible, and progress to more complex understandings with considerable reinforcement along the way. A wealth of examples – usually several dozen per chapter – offer detailed, conceptual explanations, in order to build in students a strong, cumulative foundation in the material before asking them to apply what they’ve learned. </para>

U.S. History
<para><emphasis effect="italics">U.S. History</emphasis> covers the breadth of the chronological history of the United States and also provides the necessary depth to ensure the course is manageable for instructors and students alike. U.S. History is designed to meet the scope and sequence requirements of most courses. The authors introduce key forces and major developments that together form the American experience, with particular attention paid to considering issues of race, class, and gender. The text provides a balanced approach to U.S. history, considering the people, events, and ideas that have shaped the United States from both the top down (politics, economics, diplomacy) and bottom up (eyewitness accounts, lived experience).</para>

Chemistry (cover on the webiste is incorrect)
<para><emphasis effect="italics">Chemistry</emphasis> is designed for the two-semester general chemistry course. For many students, this course provides the foundation to a career in chemistry, while for others, this may be their only college-level science course. As such, this textbook provides an important opportunity for students to learn the core concepts of chemistry and understand how those concepts apply to their lives and the world around them. The text has been developed to meet the scope and sequence of most general chemistry courses. At the same time, the book includes a number of innovative features designed to enhance student learning. A strength of Chemistry is that instructors can customize the book, adapting it to the approach that works best in their classroom.</para>

Precalculus
<para><emphasis effect="italics">Precalculus<emphasis> is intended for college-level precalculus students. Since precalculus courses vary from one institution to the next, we have attempted to meet the needs of as broad an audience as possible, including all of the content that might be covered in any particular course. The result is a comprehensive book that covers more ground than an instructor could likely cover in a typical one- or two-semester course; but instructors should find, almost without fail, that the topics they wish to include in their syllabus are covered in the text. Many chapters of Openstax College Precalculus are suitable for other freshman and sophomore math courses such as College Algebra and Trigonometry; however, instructors of those courses might need to supplement or adjust the material. OpenStax will also have <emphasis effect="italics">College Algebra</emphasis> and <emphasis effect="italics">Algebra and Trigonometry</emphasis> titles tailored to the particular scope, sequence, and pedagogy of those courses.</para>

College Physics for AP<sup>®</sup> Courses
<para><emphasis effect="italics">College Physics for AP<sup>®</sup> Courses</emphasis> is designed to engage students in their exploration of physics and help them to relate what they learn in the classroom to their lives and to apply these concepts to the Advanced Placement<sup>®</sup> test. Physics underlies much of what is happening today in other sciences and in technology, therefore the book includes interesting facts and ideas that go beyond the scope of the AP<sup>®</sup> course to further student understanding. The AP® Connection in each chapter directs students to the material they should focus on for the AP<sup>®</sup> exam, and what content — although interesting — is not necessarily part of the AP<sup>®</sup> curriculum.</para>

<para><emphasis effect="italics">College Physics for AP<sup>®</sup> Courses</emphasis> introduces topics conceptually and steadily progresses to precise definitions and analytical applications. The analytical aspect (problem solving) is tied back to the concept before moving to another topic. Each introductory chapter, for example, opens with a photograph relevant to the subject of the chapter and interesting applications that are easy for most students to visualize.</para>

Introduction to Sociology 2e
<para><emphasis effect="italics">Introduction to Sociology 2e</emphasis> adheres to the scope and sequence of a typical, one-semester introductory sociology course. It offers comprehensive coverage of core concepts, foundational scholars, and emerging theories, which are supported by a wealth of engaging learning materials. The textbook presents detailed section reviews with rich questions, discussions that help students apply their knowledge, and features that draw learners into the discipline in meaningful ways. The second edition retains the book’s conceptual organization, aligning to most courses, and has been significantly updated to reflect the latest research and provide examples most relevant to today’s students. In order to help instructors transition to the revised version, the 2e changes are described within the preface. </para>

Principles of Macroeconomics for AP<sup>®</sup> Courses
<div>
<para><emphasis effect="italics">Principles of Macroeconomics for AP<sup>®</sup> Courses</emphasis> covers the scope and sequence for a one-semester Advance Placement Macroeconomics<sup>®</sup> course. The book is on the example textbook list for the AP<sup>®</sup> course <link url="http://www.collegeboard.com/html/apcourseaudit/courses/macroeconomics_textbook_list.html" 
  window="new">here</link>. The text also includes many current examples, including the housing bubble and housing crisis, Zimbabwe’s hyperinflation, global unemployment, and the appointment of the United States’ first female Federal Reserve chair, Janet Yellen.</para>

<para>In order to more closely align to the AP<sup>®</sup> curriculum, this textbook features a more prominent section on the Expenditure-Output model, organized within the section on Keynesian Economics.</para>

<para>The pedagogical choices, chapter arrangements, and learning objective fulfillment were developed and vetted with feedback from educators dedicated to the project. The outcome is a balanced approach to economics and to the theory and application of economics concepts. Current events are treated in a politically-balanced way, as well. <emphasis effect="italics">Principles of Macroeconomics</emphasis> PDF and web view versions have been updated to include current FRED (Federal Reserve Economic) data.</para>
<div>

Principles of Microeconomics for AP<sup>®</sup> Courses
<div>
<para><emphasis effect="italics">Principles of Microeconomics for AP<sup>®</sup> Courses</emphasis> covers the scope and sequence for a one-semester Advance Placement Microeconomics<sup>®</sup>  course. The book is on the example textbook list for the AP® course <link url="http://www.collegeboard.com/html/apcourseaudit/courses/microeconomics_textbook_list.html" 
  window="new">here</link>. The text also includes many current examples, including; the Keystone Pipeline, Occupy Wall Street, and debates over the minimum wage.</para>

<para>The pedagogical choices, chapter arrangements, and learning objective fulfillment were developed and vetted with feedback from educators dedicated to the project. The outcome is a balanced approach to economics and to the theory and application of economics concepts. Current events are treated in a politically-balanced way, as well. <emphasis effect="italics">Principles of Microeconomics</emphasis> PDF and web view versions have been updated to include current FRED (Federal Reserve Economic) data.</para>
</div>
